[
    {
        "question": "Which bank was named one of the 'Best Companies for Women in India' for the ninth consecutive year?",
        "options": [
            "IndusInd Bank",
            "HDFC Bank",
            "DBS Bank India",
            "SBI"
        ],
        "answer": "DBS Bank India"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the excerpts, where does India rank globally in terms of the start-up ecosystem?",
        "options": [
            "1st",
            "2nd",
            "3rd",
            "4th"
        ],
        "answer": "3rd"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank was named one of the 'Best Companies for Women in India' for the ninth consecutive year?",
        "options": [
            "IndusInd Bank",
            "HDFC Bank",
            "DBS Bank India",
            "SBI"
        ],
        "answer": "DBS Bank India"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the excerpts, where does India rank globally in terms of the start-up ecosystem?",
        "options": [
            "1st",
            "2nd",
            "3rd",
            "4th"
        ],
        "answer": "3rd"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which three Indians have been featured in Forbes' 2024 list of the World's 100 Most Powerful Women?",
        "options": [
            "Nirmala Sitharaman, Roshni Nadar Malhotra, Kiran Mazumdar-Shaw",
            "Indra Nooyi, Roshni Nadar Malhotra, Kiran Mazumdar-Shaw",
            "Nirmala Sitharaman, Arundhati Bhattacharya, Kiran Mazumdar-Shaw",
            "Nirmala Sitharaman, Roshni Nadar Malhotra, Shikha Sharma",
            "Nirmala Sitharaman, Arundhati Bhattacharya, Roshni Nadar Malhotra"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which position does India hold in the global pharmaceutical market by volume? (December 2024)",
        "options": [
            "First",
            "Third",
            "Second",
            "Fourth",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Third"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the ranking of the Indian Men's Hockey Team in the FIH World Rankings for December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "3rd",
            "4th",
            "5th",
            "6th",
            "7th"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city set a Guinness World Record with 5,000 Acharyas reciting Gita verses?",
        "options": [
            "Varanasi",
            "Bhopal",
            "Haridwar",
            "Ujjain",
            "Ayodhya"
        ],
        "answer": "Bhopal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which position did IIT Kharagpur secure in India in the QS World University Rankings Sustainability 2025?",
        "options": [
            "1st",
            "2nd",
            "3rd",
            "5th",
            "6th"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not one of the four key pillars evaluated in the recently unveiled LEADS 2024 Report?",
        "options": [
            "Logistics Infrastructure",
            "Digital Innovation",
            "Sustainable Logistics",
            "Operating and Regulatory Environment",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What rank did India achieve in the QS Future Skills Index 2025 for job market preparedness?",
        "options": [
            "1st",
            "2nd",
            "3rd",
            "4th",
            "5th"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the record net worth achieved by Elon Musk, as per the Bloomberg Billionaires Index?",
        "options": [
            "$400 billion",
            "$450 billion",
            "$500 billion",
            "$550 billion",
            "$600 billion"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "With which bank has Department for Promotion of Industry and Internal Trade (DPIIT) signed an MoU to empower startups and foster innovation?",
        "options": [
            "ICICI Bank",
            "HDFC Bank",
            "State Bank of India",
            "Axis Bank",
            "PNB"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which app became the world's second most downloaded food & drink app?",
        "options": [
            "Swiggy",
            "Zomato",
            "Zepto",
            "Uber Eats",
            "Domino's"
        ],
        "answer": "Zepto"
    },
    {
        "question": "India ranks 3rd in which global list for 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Green Energy",
            "Smart Cities",
            "LEED Green Buildings",
            "Digital Innovation",
            "Sustainable Agriculture"
        ],
        "answer": "LEED Green Buildings"
    },
    {
        "question": "What rank did India achieve in the Corruption Perceptions Index 2024?",
        "options": [
            "50",
            "96",
            "120",
            "80",
            "60"
        ],
        "answer": "96"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country topped the Global Digital Well-Being Index with the highest score in online safety and parental support?",
        "options": [
            "United States",
            "India",
            "Australia",
            "United Kingdom",
            "Japan"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is India's rank among the top 10 countries most affected by extreme weather events over the last three decades (1993-2023), as per the Climate Risk Index (CRI) published by Greenwatch?",
        "options": [
            "4th",
            "6th",
            "8th",
            "10th",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "6th"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company ranked 2nd globally in the FutureBrand Index 2024, ahead of brands like Apple and Nike?",
        "options": [
            "Google",
            "Samsung",
            "Microsoft",
            "Reliance",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the richest woman in the world in 2025, according to the Forbes Billionaire List?",
        "options": [
            "Fran\u00e7oise Bettencourt Meyers",
            "Julia Koch",
            "Alice Walton",
            "Jacqueline Mars",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who topped Bloomberg's list of Asia's 10 richest families?",
        "options": [
            "Dhanin Chearavanont",
            "Robert Budi Hartono",
            "Pallonji Mistry",
            "Mukesh Ambani",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is India's current rank in terms of the largest metro network in the world?",
        "options": [
            "First",
            "Second",
            "Third",
            "Fourth",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "India ranks 4th in the Global Firepower Index 2025. Which country tops the Global Firepower Index 2025?",
        "options": [
            "China",
            "Russia",
            "USA",
            "Germany",
            "Pakistan"
        ],
        "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to the Oxfam report, how much wealth was extracted from India by the UK between 1765 and 1900, in today's value?",
        "options": [
            "$64.82 trillion",
            "$33.8 trillion",
            "$50 trillion",
            "$2 trillion",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "$64.82 trillion"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is India's global rank in terms of the largest start-up ecosystems as of January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "First",
            "Second",
            "Third",
            "Fourth",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "Third"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has the highest number of schools with zero enrollment according to the UDISE+ Report for 2023-24?",
        "options": [
            "Rajasthan",
            "Telangana",
            "West Bengal",
            "Madhya Pradesh",
            "Tamil Nadu"
        ],
        "answer": "West Bengal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was recently listed in the World Book of Records for his contributions as a political analyst and psephologist?",
        "options": [
            "Dr. Vishal Reddy",
            "Dr. Ramachandra Rao",
            "Dr. Praveen Pullata",
            "Dr. Chandrababu Naidu",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian institution ranked 99th in computer science in THE World Rankings 2025, marking the first time an Indian institution has been in the global top 100 for this subject?",
        "options": [
            "IIT Bombay",
            "IIT Delhi",
            "IISc Bengaluru",
            "IIT Madras",
            "IIT Roorkee"
        ],
        "answer": "IISc Bengaluru"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has topped the Fiscal Health Index (FHI) 2025 ranking launched by NITI Aayog?",
        "options": [
            "Chhattisgarh",
            "Odisha",
            "Goa",
            "Jharkhand",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    }
]